Today, I want to tell you about a pressing social issue.
اليوم، أريد ن أخبركم عن قضيةٍ اجتماعيةٍ ملحّة.
Now, it's not nuclear arms,
الآن، إنها ليست الأسلحة النووية،
it's not immigration,
إنها ليست الهجرة،
and it's not malaria.
وليست الملاريا.
I'm here to talk about movies.
أنا هنا للحديث عن الأفلام.
Now, in all seriousness, movies are actually really important.
الآن، وبكل جدية، الأفلام بالفعل مهمة حقًا.
In film, we can be wildly entertained,
في الفيلم، يمكننا أن نكون مستمتعين بشدة،
and we can also be transported through storytelling.
ويمكننا أيضًا أن ننتقل من خلال سرد القصص.
Storytelling is so important.
سرد القصص في غاية الأهمية.
Stories tell us what societies value,
القصص تحكي لنا ما هي قيمة المجتمعات،
they offer us lessons,
تقدم لنا العبر،
and they share and preserve our history.
وتشارك وتحافظ على تاريخنا.
Stories are amazing.
القصص مدهشة.
But stories don't give everyone
لكن القصص لا تعطي الجميع
the same opportunity to appear within them,
نفس الفرصة ليظهروا فيها،
particularly not stories
ولا سيّما القصص
compartmentalized in the form of American movies.
المجزأة في هيئة الأفلام الأمريكية.
In film, interestingly enough,
ومن المثير للاهتمام في الأفلام،
females are still erased and marginalized
أن الإناث مازالت تُمسَح وتهمش
in a lot of our stories.
في كثيرٍ من قصصنا.
And I learned this for the first time about 10 years ago
وعلمت هذا للمرة الأولى من حوالي 10 سنوات
when I did my first study on gender role in G-rated films.
عندما أجريت أول دراسة لي عن أدوار الجنسين في أفلام الفئة G.
Since then, we've conducted more than 30 investigations.
ومنذ ذلك الوقت، قمنا بإجراء أكثر من 30 تحقيقًا.
My team is tired.
فريقي مُتْعَب.
And I've committed my life
وقد كرست حياتي
as researcher and activist
كباحثة وناشطة
to fighting the inclusion crisis
لمحاربة أزمة التضمين
in Hollywood.
في هوليوود.
So today, what I'd like to do is tell you about that crisis.
لذلك اليوم، ما أود القيام به هو أن أخبركم عن تلك الأزمة.
I want to talk about gender inequality in film.
أريد أن أتحدث عن عدم المساواة بين الجنسين في الأفلام.
I want to tell you how it is perpetuated,
أريد أن أخبركم عن كيفية استمرارها،
and then I'm going to tell you how we're going to fix it.
وبعد ذلك سأقول لكم كيف سنقوم بإصلاحها.
However, one caveat before I begin:
مع ذلك، هناك تحفظ واحد قبل أن أبدأ:
my data are really depressing.
بياناتي محبِطة حقًّا.
So I want to apologize in advance,
ولذلك أود أن أعتذر مقدَّمًا،
because I'm going to put you all in a really bad mood.
لأنني سأضعكم جميعًا في مزاج سيء حقًا.
But I'm going to bring it up at the end,
ولكنّي سأجعله أفضل في النهاية،
and I'm going to present a silver lining
وسأقدم لكم الجانب المشرق
to fix this mess that we've been in
لإصلاح هذه الفوضى التي نحن فيها
for a very, very long time.
من مدة طويلة جدًا.
So, let's start with the gravity of the situation.
لذا، دعونا نبدأ مع جسامة هذا الوضع.
Each year, my research team examines the top 100 grossing films
في كل عام، يدرس فريقي البحثي أفضل 100 فيلم
in the United States.
في الولايات المتحدة.
What we do is we look at every speaking or named character on-screen.
ما نقوم به هو أننا ننظر لكل شخصية ناطقة أو مسماة على الشاشة.
Now, to count in one of my investigations,
الآن، لعد الشخصيات في دراساتي،
all a character has to do is say one word.
كل ما على الشخصية فعله هو قول كلمة واحدة.
This is a very low bar.
هذا حَدّ منخفض جدًا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Thus far, we've looked at 800 movies,
حتى الآن، بحثنا في 800 فيلم،
from 2007 to 2015,
من 2007 حتى 2015،
cataloguing every speaking character on-screen for gender, race, ethnicity,
وقمنا بجدولة كل شخصية ناطقة على الشاشة بناءً على الجنس والعرق والإنتماء العرقي
LGBT and characters with a disability.
والمثليين والمتحولين جنسيًا والشخصيات ذوي الإعاقة.
Let's take a look at really some problematic trends.
دعونا نلقي نظرة على بعض المؤشرات الإشكالية حقًا.
First, females are still noticeably absent on-screen in film.
أولًا، ما تزال الإناث غائبات بشكل ملحوظ من الظهور في الأفلام.
Across 800 movies and 35,205 speaking characters,
من 800 فيلم و 35,205 شخصية ناطقة،
less than a third of all roles go to girls and women.
أقل من ثلث الأدوار تذهب للفتيات والنساء.
Less than a third!
أقل من الثلث!
There's been no change from 2007 to 2015,
لم يطرأ أي تغيير من 2007 حتى 2015،
and if you compare our results
وإذا قارنت نتائجنا
to a small sample of films from 1946 to 1955,
بعينة صغيرة من الأفلام من 1946 حتى 1955،
there's been no change in over a half of a century.
لم يكن هناك أي تغيير منذ أكثر من نصف قرن.
Over half of a century!
أكثر من نصف قرن!
But we're half of the population.
ولكننا نصف التعداد السكاني.
Now, if we look at this data intersectionally,
الآن، إذا نظرنا لهذه البيانات بشكلٍ متعدد الجوانب،
which has been a focus of today,
والذي كان محور التركيز اليوم،
the picture becomes even more problematic.
فإن الصورة تصبح أكثر إشكالية.
Across the top 100 films of just last year,
عبر أفضل 100 فيلم من العام الماضي فقط،
48 films didn't feature one black or African-American speaking character,
48 فيلمًا لم تُظهر شخصية واحدة سوداء أو أفريقية أمريكية ناطقة،
not one.
ولا واحدة.
70 films were devoid of Asian or Asian-American speaking characters
70 فيلمًا كانوا خاليين من الشخصيات الآسيوية أو الآسيوية الأمريكية الناطقة
that were girls or women.
من الفتيات والنساء.
None.
لا أحد.
Eighty-four films didn't feature one female character that had a disability.
84 فيلم لم يُظهِروا ولا شخصية واحدة نسائية تعاني من إعاقة.
And 93 were devoid of lesbian, bisexual or transgender female speaking characters.
و93 خالية من الشخصيات النسائية الناطقة المثلية أو ثنائية الجنس أو المتحولة جنسيا.
This is not underrepresentation.
هذا ليس نقص تمثيل.
This is erasure,
هذا محو،
and I call this the epidemic of invisibility.
وأنا أدعو هذا بوباء الخفاء.
Now, when we move from prevalence to protagonist,
الآن، حين ننتقل من الغلبة إلى أدوار البطولة،
the story is still problematic.
لاتزال القصة إشكالية.
Out of a hundred films last year,
من أصل 100 فيلم من العام الماضي،
only 32 featured a female lead or colead driving the action.
32 فقط أظهروا بطولة نسائية أو بطولة مشتركة لتقود الأحداث.
Only three out of a hundred films
فقط ثلاثة من أصل 100 فيلم
featured an underrepresented female driving the story,
أظهروا نساء منقوصات التمثيل لتقودن الأحداث،
and only one diverse woman
وامرأة واحدة مختلفة فقط
that was 45 years of age or older at the time of theatrical release.
والتي كانت تبلغ 45 عامًا أو أكثر في وقت إطلاق الفيلم.
Now let's look at portrayal.
لننظر الآن إلى التصوير.
In addition to the numbers you just saw,
بالإضافة إلى الأرقام التي شاهدتموها للتو،
females are far more likely to be sexualized in film
غالبًا ما تُصَوًّر النساء في الأفلام بطريقة جنسية
than their male counterparts.
أكثر من نظرائهم من الرجال.
Matter of fact, they're about three times as likely
في الواقع، هن حوالي ثلاث مرات أرجح
to be shown in sexually revealing clothing,
لأن يظهرن بملابس كاشفة بطريقة جنسية
partially naked,
أو شبه عاريات
and they're far more likely to be thin.
وأكثر احتمالًا أن تكن نحيفات.
Now, sometimes, in animation, females are so thin
في بعض الأحيان، في الرسوم المتحركة، تكون الإناث نحيفات جدًا
that their waist size approximates the circumference of their upper arm.
لدرجة أن يكون خصرها يقارب محيط أعلى ذارعها.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
We like to say that these gals have no room for a womb
ممكن أن نقول أن هؤلاء الفتيات ليست لديهن أي مساحة لوجود الرحم
or any other internal organ.
أو أي عضو داخلي آخر.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Now, all joking aside,
الآن، لنضع المزاح جانبًا،
theories suggest, research confirms,
تشير النظريات وتؤكد الأبحاث:
exposure to thin ideals and objectifying content
التعرض للقدوات النحيفة وتجسيم المحتوى
can lead to body dissatisfaction, internalization of the thin ideal
قد يؤدي إلى عدم الرضا عن الجسم، واستبطان القدوة النحيفة
and self-objectification among some female viewers.
وتشييء الذات بين بعض المشاهدين من النساء.
Obviously, what we see on-screen
من الواضح، أن ما نراه على الشاشة
and what we see in the world,
وما نراه في الواقع،
they do not match.
لا يتطابقان.
They do not match!
إنها لا تتطابق!
Matter of fact, if we lived in the screen world,
في حقيقة الأمر، إذا عشنا في عالم الشاشة،
we would have a population crisis on our hands.
ستكون لدينا أزمة سكانية بين يدينا.
So, as soon as I recognized these patterns,
لذلك، سرعان ما تعرفت على هذه الأنماط،
I wanted to find out why,
كنت أرغب في معرفة السبب،
and it turns out that there are two drivers to inequality on-screen:
وتبين أن هناك عاملين لعدم المساواة على الشاشة:
content creator gender and misperceptions of the audience.
جنس صانع المحتوى وسوء الفهم من الجمهور.
Let's unpack them really quick.
دعونا نستعرض ذلك سريعًا.
If you want to change any of the patterns I just talked about,
إذا أردت تغيير أيًا من النماذج التي تحدثت عنها للتو،
all you have to do is hire female directors.
كل ما عليك فعله هو تعيين مخرجات إناث.
Turns out, the female directors
اتضح أن المخرجات الإناث،
are associated with, in terms of short films and indie films,
فيما يتعلق بالأفلام القصيرة والأفلام المستقلة،
more girls and women on-screen,
مقترنات بوجود فتيات ونساء أكثر على الشاشة،
more stories with women in the center,
وقصص أكثر حيث النساء في المحور،
more stories with women 40 years of age or older on-screen,
وقصص أكثر مع نساء في الأربعين من العمر أو أكبر على الشاشة،
which I think is good news for this crowd.
والتي أعتقد أنها أخبار سارة لهذا الحشد.
More underrepresented --
المزيد من الشخصيات ناقصة التمثيل --
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Sorry.
آسفة.
Sorry but not sorry.
أعتذز ولكنّي لست آسفة.
More underrepresented characters in terms of race and ethnicity,
المزيد من الشخصيات الممثلة تمثيلًا ناقصًا من حيث العرق والإثنية،
and most importantly,
والأهم من ذلك،
more women working behind the camera
المزيد من النساء العاملات خلف الكاميرا
in key production roles.
في أدوار الإنتاج الرئيسية.
Easy answer to the problems that we just talked about.
إجابة سهلة للمشاكل التي تحدثنا عنها للتو.
Or is it?
هل هي كذلك؟
It's actually not.
إنها في الواقع ليست كذلك.
800 films, 2007-2015,
800 فيلم، 2007-2015
886 directors.
886 مُخرجًا.
Only 4.1 percent are women.
4.1% فقط من النساء.
Only three are African-American or black,
ثلاثة فقط هم من أصل أفريقي أمريكي أو أسود،
and only one woman was Asian.
وامرأة واحدة فقط آسيوية.
So why is it so difficult
فلماذا من الصعب جدًا
to have female directors
أن يكون هناك مخرجات إناث
if they're part of the solution?
إذا كن يُشكِّلن جزءًا من الحل؟
Well, to answer this question,
حسنًا، للإجابة على هذا السؤال،
we conducted a study.
قمنا بإجراء دراسة.
We interviewed dozens of industry insiders
أجرينا مقابلات مع العشرات من العاملين في الصناعة
and asked them about directors.
وسألناهم عن المخرجين.
Turns out, both male and female executives,
تبين أن كلًا من الذكور والإناث من المسؤولين التنفذيين،
when they think director,
عندما يفكرون في المخرج،
they think male.
يفكرون في الذكور.
They perceive the traits of leadership
يرون أن سمات القيادة
to be masculine in nature.
يجب أن تكون ذكورية في طبيعتها.
So when they're going to hire a director
لذلك عندما يوظفون مخرجًا
to command a crew, lead a ship,
لقيادة الطاقم وقيادة السفينة
be a visionary or be General Patton,
ويكون ذو بصيرة أو يكون (الجنرال باتون)،
all the things that we've heard --
كل الأشياء التي سمعناها --
their thoughts and ideations pull male.
أفكارهم وتصوراتهم تختار الذكور.
The perception of director or a leader
تصور المخرج أو المدير
is inconsistent with the perception of a woman.
لا يتسق مع تصور المرأة.
The roles are incongruous,
الأدوار متضاربة،
which is consistent with a lot of research in the psychological arena.
وهو ما يتسق مع الكثير من البحوث في المجال النفسي.
Second factor contributing to inequality on-screen
العامل الثاني الذي يساهم في عدم المساواة على الشاشة
is misperceptions of the audience.
هو سوء الفهم من الجمهور.
I don't need to tell this crowd:
لا أحتاج أن أخبر هذا الحشد:
50 percent of the people that go to the box office and buy tickets
50% من الناس الذين يذهبون إلى شباك التذاكر ويشترونها
are girls and women in this country.
هم من الفتيات والنساء في هذا البلد.
Right?
صحيح؟
But we're not perceived to be a viable or financially lucrative target audience.
لكن لا يُنظر إلينا كمجهور مستهدف مربح ماديًا وقابل للاستمرار.
Further, there's some misperceptions
وعلاوة على ذلك، هناك بعض التصورات الخاطئة
about whether females can open a film.
حول ما إذا كانت الإناث تستطيع فتح فيلم.
Open a film means that if you place a female at the center,
فتح الفيلم يعني أنه إذا كنت تضع أنثى في محور القصة،
it doesn't have the return on investment
لن تحصل على العائد على الاستثمار
that if you place a male at the center of a story does.
كما لو ضعت ذكرًا كمحور للقصة.
This misperception is actually costly.
هذا الفهم الخاطئ مكلف فعلًا.
Right?
صحيح؟
Especially in the wake of franchise successes
خاصة في أعقاب نجاحات متميزة
like "The Hunger Games,"
مثل "The Hunger Games"،
"Pitch Perfect"
"Pitch Perfect"
or that small little indie film, "Star Wars: The Force Awakens."
أو ذلك الفيلم الصغير المستقل، "Star Wars: The Force Awakens".
Our own economic analyses show that gender of the lead character
تشير تحليلاتنا الاقتصادية أن جنس الشخصية الرئيسية
doesn't play a role in economic success in the United States.
ليس له أي دور في النجاح الاقتصادي في الولايات المتحدة.
But what does?
ولكن ما الذي له دور؟
Production costs alone
تكاليف الإنتاج وحدها
or in conjunction with how widely a film is distributed in this country.
أو بالاشتراك مع مدى انتشار وتوزيع الفيلم في هذا البلد.
It's not the gender of the lead character.
وليس جنس الشخصية الرئيسية.
So at this point, we should all be sufficiently depressed.
حتى هذه النقطة، ينبغي أن نكون جميعًا مكتئبين بما فيه الكفاية.
No change in 50 years,
لم يطرأ أي تغيير منذ 50 عامًا،
few female directors working behind the camera
عدد قليل من المخرجات يعملن خلف الكاميرات
and the entertainment industry does not trust us as an audience.
وصناعة الترفيه لا تثق بنا كجمهور.
Well, I told you there would be a silver lining,
حسنًا، لقد أخبرتكم أن هناك جانب مشرق،
and there is.
وهو موجود.
There are actually simple and tangible solutions
هناك في الواقع حلول بسيطة وملموسة
to fixing this problem
لإصلاح هذه المشكلة
that involve content creators,
والتي تشمل صنّاع المحتوى،
executives and consumers
والمديرين التنفيذيين والمستهلكين
like the individuals in this room.
مثل جميع الأفراد في هذه القاعة.
Let's talk about a few of them.
دعونا نتحدث عن عدد قليل منهم.
The first is what I call "just add five."
الأول ما أدعوه ب"فقط أضف خمسة".
Did you know if we looked at the top 100 films next year
هل تعلمون أننا لو نظرنا إلى أفضل 100 فيلم في العام المقبل
and simply added five female speaking characters on-screen
وأضفنا خمس شخصيات نسائية ناطقة على الشاشة
to each of those films,
لكل من تلك الأفلام،
it would create a new norm.
ذلك من شأنه أن يخلق قاعدة جديدة.
If we were to do this for three contiguous years,
إن فعلنا هذا لثلاث سنواتٍ متصلة،
we would be at gender parity
ستكون لدينا مساواة بين الجنسين
for the first time in over a half of a century.
للمرة الأولى منذ أكثر من نصف قرن.
Now, this approach is advantageous for a variety of reasons.
هذا النهج مفيد لمجموعة متنوعة من الأسباب.
One? It doesn't take away jobs for male actors.
الأول؟ أنه لا يسلب فرص العمل من الممثلين الذكور.
Heaven forbid.
لا سمح الله.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Two, it's actually cost-effective. It doesn't cost that much.
الثاني، أنها فعّالة من حيث التكلفة. إنها لا تكلف كثيرًا.
Three, it builds a pipeline for talent.
الثالث، إنها تبني خطًا للمواهب.
And four, it humanizes the production process.
والرابع، أنها تجعل عملية الإنتاج متحضرة.
Why? Because it makes sure that there's women on set.
لماذا؟ لأنها تضمن وجود نساء في موقع التصوير.
Second solution is for A-list talent.
الحل الثاني هو لنجوم الصف الأول.
A-listers, as we all know, can make demands in their contracts,
كما نعرف جميعًا أن نجوم الصف الأول بإمكانهم إضافة مطالب لعقودهم،
particularly the ones that work on the biggest Hollywood films.
وخاصة أولئك الذين يعملون على أكبر أفلام هوليوود.
What if those A-listers
ماذا لو قام هؤلاء النجوم
simply added an equity clause or an inclusion rider
بإضافة بند للمساواة أو التضمين
into their contract?
في عقودهم؟
Now, what does that mean?
الآن، ماذا يعني ذلك؟
Well, you probably don't know
حسنًا، من الغالب أنك لا تعرف هذا
but the typical feature film
ولكن الفيلم الطويل العادي
has about 40 to 45 speaking characters in it.
يحتوي على 40 إلى 45 شخصية ناطقة.
I would argue that only 8 to 10 of those characters
أنا أزعم أنه من 8 إلى 10 شخيصات فقط من تلك الشخصيات
are actually relevant to the story.
هي في الواقع ذات صلة بالقصة.
Except maybe "Avengers." Right?
باستثناء ربما فيلم "Avengers". أليس كذلك؟
A few more in "Avengers."
هناك عدد أكثر في فيلم "Avengers".
The remaining 30 or so roles,
ثلاثون أو نحو ذلك من الأدوار المتبقية،
there's no reason why those minor roles
ليس هناك سبب يجعل هذه الأدوار الثانوية
can't match or reflect the demography
لا تتطابق أو تعكس التركيبة السكانية
of where the story is taking place.
للمكان الذي تحدث فيه القصة.
An equity rider by an A-lister in their contract
إدارج النجوم لملحق مساواة في عقودهم
can stipulate that those roles
يمكن أن ينص على أن تلك الأدوار
reflect the world in which we actually live.
يجب أن تعكس العالم الذي نعيش فيه فعلًا.
Now, there's no reason why a network,
وليس هناك سبب يدعو الشبكة،
a studio or a production company
أوالاستوديو أو شركة الإنتاج
cannot adopt the same contractual language
لعدم اعتماد نفس اللغة التعاقدية
in their negotiation processes.
في عملياتهم التفاوضية.
Third solution:
الحل الثالث:
this would be for the entertainment industry,
وهذا سيكون لصناعة الترفيه،
Hollywood in particular,
هوليوود على وجه الخصوص،
to adopt the Rooney Rule
لاعتماد "قاعدة روني"
when it comes to hiring practices around directors.
عندما يتعلق الأمر بممارسات التوظيف عند المخرجين.
Now, in the NFL, the Rooney Rule stipulates
الآن، في اتحاد كرة القدم الأمريكي، تنص قاعدة روني على
that if a team wants to hire a coach from outside the organization,
أنه إذا أراد فريق تعيين مدرب من خارج المنظمة،
what they have to do is interview an underrepresented candidate.
ما يجب عليهم فعله هو إجراء مقابلة مع مرشح من منقوصي التمثيل.
The exact same principle can apply to Hollywood films.
نفس المبدأ يمكن أن يطبق على أفلام هوليوود.
How?
كيف؟
Well, on these top films,
حسنًا، في هذه الأفلام العليا،
executives and agents can make sure
المديرين التنفيذيين والوكلاء يمكنهم التأكد
that women and people of color are not only on the consideration list,
أن النساء والملونين ليسوا فقط على قائمة الاعتبار،
but they're actually interviewed for the job.
ولكن تمت مقابلتهم فعليًا من أجل الوظيفة.
Now, one might say,
الآن، يمكن للمرء أن يقول،
why is this important?
لماذا هذا مهم؟
Because it exposes or introduces executives to female directors
لأنه يعرض أو يقدم المديرين التنفيذيين للمخرجات الإناث
who otherwise fall prey to exclusionary hiring practices.
اللاتي يقعن فريسة لممارسات التوظيف الإقصائية.
The fourth solution
الحل الرابع
is for consumers like me and you.
وهو للمستهلكين مثلي ومثلكم.
If we want to see more films by, for and about women,
إذا أردنا أن نرى المزيد من الأفلام المصنوعة من قِبل ولأجل وحول النساء
we have to support them.
يجب علينا دعمهن.
It may mean going to the independent theater chain
وقد يعني هذا الذهاب إلى سلسلة المسارح المستقلة
instead of the multiplex.
بدلًا من المتعددة.
Or it might mean scrolling down a little further online
أو قد يعني النزول بالقائمة إلى أسفل أكثر قليلًا على الانترنت
to find a film by a female director.
لتجد فيلمًا لمخرجة أنثى.
Or it may be writing a check and funding a film,
أو قد يكون كتابة شيك وتمويل فيلم،
particularly by a female director from an underrepresented background.
ولاسيما من جانب مخرجة من خلفية ناقصة التمثيل.
Right?
صحيح؟
We need to write, call and email companies
نحن بحاجة إلى الكتابة والاتصال ومراسلة الشركات
that are making and distributing films,
التي تصنع وتوزع الأفلام،
and we need to post on our social media accounts
ونحن بحاجة لأن ننشر على حساباتنا للتواصل الاجتماعي
when we want to see inclusive representation,
عندما نريد أن نرى التمثيل الشامل،
women on-screen,
النساء على الشاشة،
and most importantly, women behind the camera.
و الأهم من ذلك، نساء خلف الكاميرا.
We need to make our voices heard and our dollars count.
نحن بحاجة إلى أن نجعل أصواتنا مسموعة وأموالنا مؤثرة.
Now, we actually have the ability to change the world on this one.
الآن، لدينا بالفعل القدرة على تغيير العالم في هذه الحالة.
The US and its content,
الولايات المتحدة ومحتواها،
films in particular,
الأفلام على وجه الخصوص،
have captured the imaginations of audiences worldwide.
قد استحوذت على خيال الجماهير في جميع أنحاء العالم.
Worldwide.
في جميع أنحاء العالم.
So that means that the film industry has unprecedented access
وهذا يعني أن صناعة السينما لديها وصول غير مسبوق
to be able to distribute stories about equality
لتكون قادرة على توزيع قصص عن المساواة
all around the world.
في جميع أنحاء العالم.
Imagine what would happen
تخيل ما سيحدث
if the film industry aligned its values
إذا أيدت صناعة السينما قيمها
with what it shows on-screen.
مع ما يعرض على الشاشة.
It could foster inclusion
يمكن أن تعزز التضمين
and acceptance for girls and women,
والقبول للفتيات والنساء،
people of color,
والملونين،
the LGBT community,
ومجتمع المثليين،
individuals with disabilities,
والأفراد ذوي الإعاقة،
and so many more around the world.
وغير ذلك الكثير في جميع أنحاء العالم.
The only thing that the film industry has to do is unleash its secret weapon,
الشيء الوحيد الذي على صناعة السينما القيام به هو إطلاق العنان لسلاحها السري،
and that's storytelling.
وهو رواية القصص.
Now, at the beginning of this talk,
الآن، في بداية هذه المحادثة،
I said that films --
قلت أن الأفلام --
that they can actually transport us,
أنها يمكن أن تنقلنا فعلًا،
but I would like to argue that films, they can transform us.
ولكن أود القول بأن الأفلام، يمكنها أن تغيرنا.
None of us in this room
لا أحد منا في هذه القاعة
have grown up or experienced a storytelling landscape
نشأ أو تعرض لراوية قصة
with fully realized female characters,
تحققت كليًا بشخصيات نسائية،
none of us,
لا أحد منّا،
because the numbers haven't changed.
لأن الأرقام لم تتغير.
What would happen if the next generation of audiences
ماذا سيحدث إذا كان الجيل القادم من الجماهير
grew up with a whole different screen reality?
نشأ مع واقع مختلف تمامًا على الشاشة؟
What would happen?
ما الذي سيحدث؟
Well I'm here to tell you today
حسنًا أنا هنا اليوم لأخبركم
that it's not only possible to change what we see on-screen
أنه ليس من الممكن فقط تغيير ما نراه على الشاشة
but I am impatient for it to get here.
لكنني أتوق لوصولها إلى ذلك.
So let's agree to take action today
لذلك دعونا نتفق على اتخاذ إجراء اليوم
to eradicate the epidemic of invisibility.
للقضاء على وباء الخفاء.
And let's agree to take action today
ودعونا نتفق على اتخاذ إجراء اليوم
to agree that US audiences and global viewers
للاتفاق على أن جماهير الولايات المتحدة والمشاهدين العالميين
demand and deserve more.
يطلبون ويستحقون أكثر.
And let's agree today
ولنتفق اليوم
that the next generation of viewers and audiences,
أن الجيل القادم من المشاهدين والجماهير،
that they deserve to see the stories
يستحقون رؤية قصص
we were never able to see.
لم نكن قادرين على رؤيتها أبدًا.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)